# Andrew David Katz

Andrewdkatz@gmail.com Washington d.c 20001 571-420-6245

### **Professional Profile**

Detail-oriented journeyman with 15+ years' experience of theatrical rigging, electrical system set-up, audio, lighting, carpentry, mechanical troubleshooting and repair. Maintaining optimal on-site safety in accordance to OSHA, ANSI, Fall Protection and various standards for safe equipment operation. Experience with hydraulic and pneumatic automation systems, interpreting and creating construction plans in AutoCAD and Vector Works.

#### **Core Qualifications**

- Safety Coordinator
- Production Management Experience
- Crew acquisition
- Rigging Specialist
- Sales
- Rigging Supervisor
- Risk Management
- Certified in Safety Standards and Procedures
- Rigging Up / Ground

- Event Fire Fighter
- Theatrical Electrician
- Profit and Loss Statements
- Event oversight
- Fork Lift/ Scissor Lift/ Knuckle Boom/ Boom Lift/Snorkel/ Reach Truck & Electronic Pallet Lift Certified
- Vendor Sourcing
- Event Marketing

## **Professional Experience of Production Management & Crew Leadership**

- Crew Sourcing
- Stage Manager
- Crew Acquisition
- Vendor Sourcing
- Problem Solving
- Equipment Sourcing
- Equipment Acquisition
- Equipment Protection
- Building Superintendent
- Quality Assurance Manager

- Marketing
- Fleet Maintenance
- Fleet Management
- Scheduling
- Waste Management
- Consumables Management
- Workplace Safety Manager
- Herding Cats
- Excellent Upselling Skills
- Loss Prevention

### **Personal**

- Highly Motivated
- Equipment Management
- Excellent Communicator (Written, Verbal, and Email)
- Team Player

- Self Starter
- Excellent Interpersonal Skills
- Time Management
- Leadership Training

# **Work History**

Communication Engineering Inc.	Rigging Supervisor	2017 - Present
The Crew Works MD	Rigger	2014 - Present
I.A.T.S.E Local 22, D.C.	Theatrical Technician / Rigger	2005 – Present
Serenity Hills Farm	Farm Foreman	2008- 2014

### **Education**

Full Sail Real World Education A.S. Recording Arts